Ibragim Zubailov

□ +385 68 458679 | 🌶 Telegram | @ karlson.zim@gmail.com | 🖬 LinkedIn | 🗘 Github | 🗞 Portfolio | 🕈 Montenegro

SKILLS

Programming: Golang, Typescript, Node.js, PHP, NestJS, Web3(Blockchain)

Storage&MQ: Clickhouse, Postgres, MySQL, Redis, Aerospike, Kafka, RabbitMQ, NATS Others: GlusterFS, ElasticSearch, Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible, Nginx, Prometheus, Grafana

Languages: Russian (native), English (intermediate)

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a Software engineer and leader with a 7 years of experience, with strong fundamentals in Node.js, Golang, Architecture and Database knowledge.

My expertise in handling high-load systems has provided me with the knowledge to craft optimal application architecture, conduct A/B testing, and transition from monolithic to microservice systems, catering to both business requirements and overall team efficiency. I've consistently analyzed every aspect of third-party technology implementation, risk assessment, transition phases, and understanding the pros/cons derived from their usage.

WORK EXPERIENCE (6.5 YEARS)

MTS Group Senior Golang and Node.js Developer

 $Moscow,\ Russia$

Jun 2022 — Jun 2023

- Develop high-load b2b storage.
- Service for optimizing load-balance of storage throughput.
- Optimized retrieve data from storage.

Stack: Golang, Node.js, Kafka, Clickhouse, RabbitMQ, GlusterFS

Lofty Teamlead (8 backend)

Moscow, Russia

 $\mathrm{May}\ 2020 - \mathrm{May}\ 2022$

- Developed arbitrage project between advertisers(DSP) and supply platforms (SSP). Actively participated in strategizing business logic development. After 2 years project was generating over 1mil\$ revenue, and having 500k rps.
- Processes added to the team: KPI performance review, roadmap planning, mentoring, idea submission point, task decoupling.
- Developed traffic quality evaluation system to predict prices for SSP
- Developed filter system to screen out fraudulent and low-quality traffic.

Stack: Golang, Aerospike, Kafka, Clickhouse, Postgres, GRPC

Techlead (4 backend)

Oct 2019 — May 2020

- Rewrote main application to achieve: stability(no fires), 3x perfomance, A/B Business testing, unit/integration tests, low entry threshold(for newcomers). In 2y growed from 15k to 150k rps.
- Introduced Agile pipeline, involved in the recruitment process
- Participated in architecture design including devop's and database storage parts.

Stack: Node.js, Clickhouse, Postgres, Redis, Kafka

Senior Node.js Developer

 $Jul \ 2019 - Oct \ 2019$

- Develop high-load (70k rps) push advertisement sender, with a big flexibility of settings.
- Microservice for authorization

Stack: Node.js, MySQL, RabbitMQ

Belsona Investment Group Middle Node.js Developer

Moscow, Russia Jun 2017 — Jul 2019

- Develop arbitrage bot between blockchain smart-contract and exchange (Binance/Bitfinex).
- Design and develop risk evaluation system and a predictive model based on market trends, trading data, blockchain activities.
- Automation scripts for reducing routine tasks, specifically for ICO projects
- Devised service for risk score ICO products.

Stack: Node.js, MySQL, Typescript, Web3(Ethereum), Websockets

EDUCATION